https://programmingzen.com/privacy-policy/

HomePrivacy
Facebook
If you require any more information or have any questions about our privacy policy, please feel free to contact us by email at info@programmingzen.com.
At programmingzen.com, the privacy of our visitors is of extreme importance to us. This privacy policy document outlines the types of personal information is received and collected by programmingzen.com and how it is used.
Who we are
Our website address is: https://programmingzen.com.
What personal data we collect and why we collect it
Comments
When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.
An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: https://automattic.com/privacy/. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.
Media
If you upload images to the website, you should avoid uploading images with embedded location data (EXIF GPS) included. Visitors to the website can download and extract any location data from images on the website.
Subscription Forms
We securely store your information collected through our subscription forms through Mailchimp, which acts as our data processor. You’ll find their privacy policy here: https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/
When you subscribe to our site, you give us permission to email you new posts and other messages that might contain affiliate links or be commercial in nature.
Cookies
If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to save your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.
If you have an account and you log in to this site, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser.
When you log in, we will also set up several cookies to save your login information and your screen display choices. Login cookies last for two days, and screen options cookies last for a year. If you select “Remember Me”, your login will persist for two weeks. If you log out of your account, the login cookies will be removed.
If you edit or publish an article, an additional cookie will be saved in your browser. This cookie includes no personal data and simply indicates the post ID of the article you just edited. It expires after 1 day.
DoubleClick DART Cookie
Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on www.programmingzen.com.
Google’s use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to your users based on their visit to www.programmingzen.com and other sites on the Internet.
Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy at the following URL – https://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html
Some of our advertising partners may use cookies and web beacons on our site. Our advertising partners include:
Google Adsense
Amazon
Clickbank
Share-a-sale
BuyAndSellAds
These third-party ad servers or ad networks use technology to the advertisements and links that appear on www.programmingzen.com send directly to your browsers. They automatically receive your IP address when this occurs. Other technologies (such as cookies, JavaScript, or Web Beacons) may also be used by the third-party ad networks to measure the effectiveness of their advertisements and/or to personalize the advertising content that you see.
programmingzen.com has no access to or control over these cookies that are used by third-party advertisers.
You should consult the respective privacy policies of these third-party ad servers for more detailed information on their practices as well as for instructions about how to opt-out of certain practices. programmingzen.com’s privacy policy does not apply to, and we cannot control the activities of, such other advertisers or websites.
If you wish to disable cookies, you may do so through your individual browser options. More detailed information about cookie management with specific web browsers can be found at the browsers’ respective websites.
Log Files
Like many other Web sites, www.programmingzen.com makes use of log files. The information inside the log files includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, type of browser, Internet Service Provider (ISP), date/time stamp, referring/exit pages, and the number of clicks to analyze trends, administer the site, track user’s movement around the site, and gather demographic information. IP addresses and other such information are not linked to any information that is personally identifiable.
Embedded content from other websites
Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.
These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracking your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.
Analytics
We collect visitors’ data through Google Analytics for the purpose of analyzing and improving our site performance and traffic. Our retention policy is 26 months. You’ll find their privacy policy here: https://policies.google.com/privacy
Who we share your data with
Google Analytics — Visitor statistics. Privacy Policy.
Youtube — Embedded Videos, may track your usage when you play a video. Privacy Policy.
MailChimp — Our mailing list/newsletter provider for sending emails. Privacy Policy.
How long we retain your data
If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.
For users that register on our website (if any), we also store the personal information they provide in their user profile. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (except they cannot change their username). Website administrators can also see and edit that information.
What rights you have over your data
If you have an account on this site, or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.
Where we send your data
Visitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service.
Your contact information
This site is operated by Netrich Media. You can contact us at info@netrichmedia.com or by phone at (530) 428-5543.
Additional information
What data breach procedures we have in place
In case of a breach of data, we’ll inform our users on the site and via the mailing list within 72 hours and proceed to an as fast as possible technical resolution.
Updates
We may update this privacy policy from time to time in order to reflect changes to our practices or for other operational, legal or regulatory reasons.
Share this:TwitterFacebook
Facebook
Leave a Reply					Cancel reply
This site uses Akismet to reduce spam. Learn how your comment data is processed.
